Over there, huh...
（パックン）あそこか
Any closer and I'll be noticed...
（パックン）
これ以上 近づくと気づかれるか
Nee-chan...
（エビゾウ）姉ちゃん
Are you taking those
with you?
そいつを持っていくのか？
Fate must have meant
for this to happen...
（チヨ）これも何かの縁じゃ
Nothing will serve me better
than these
あやつと やり合うのに
これ以上のものはないからな
if I'm gonna fight against him...
I've lived too long a life...
わしも長生きしすぎた
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
～♪
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
The Retired Granny's Determination
So... that's where his hideout is.
（はたけカカシ）なるほど
ここに ヤツらのアジトが
Most likely.
おそらくな
Gaara's scent was also coming
from that same place.
我愛羅のにおいも
同じ場所からしとった
I see.
（カカシ）なるほど
I have one more favor to ask you.
もう１つ 頼みがあるんだけど
Huh?
（パックン）ん？
（ナルト）う～ん
おっ うくっ…
いっ たたた…
Hey, are you awake, Naruto?
（パックン）
おう 起きたか ナルト
Huh? Pakkun...
（ナルト）あれ パックン
Okay, Pakkun, I'm counting on you.
（カカシ）
じゃあ パックン よろしく
See you around then, Naruto!
じゃあ またな ナルト
（ナルト）あっ
Kakashi-sensei!
カカシ先生
Could it be that you've found
the Akatsuki's hideout?
ひょっとして
暁あかつきのアジトが分かったのか？
Yeah... We're heading out immediately.
（カカシ）ああ すぐに出発するぞ
うん
What, Gaara's whereabouts
have been–?!
（テマリ）
何？ 我愛羅の居場所が？
Yes ma'am! His whereabouts
have just been located.
（砂すなの里さとの忍）
はい 先ほど判明したそうです
The Leaf are preparing
to depart immediately!
木こノ葉はの方々は
すぐに出発するとのことです
Understood! Gather
our skilled men immediately!
（テマリ）分かった
こちらも すぐに手練てだれを用意しろ
I will be heading out as well!
（テマリ）私も出る
（砂の里の忍）はっ
Yes, ma'am!
Temari...
（カンクロウ）テマリ
（カンクロウ）うっ…
Kankuro, don't be so reckless!
カンクロウ ムチャだ
You need to stay in bed
and take it easy!
お前は おとなしく寝てろ
I will get Gaara back,
no matter what!
我愛羅は 必ずこの手で取り戻す
All right, as soon
as the Sand is ready,
（カカシ）
では 砂の用意ができしだい
we'll join them for Gaara's rescue.
彼らと共に
我愛羅君を救出に向かう
Got it?
いいな
Sorry to have kept you waiting!
（テマリ）待たせたな
（春野はるのサクラ）あっ テマリさん
Temari-san!
Everyone's here...
（カカシ）そろったな
All right! Then let's head out!
よーし
じゃあ 出発だってばよ
Wait!
（バキ）待て
（ナルト）あ？
Temari... You and the others stay here
in the village and patrol the border.
テマリ お前たちは
里に残って国境警備に当たれ
What do you mean by that?!
どういうことだ それは
That's an order from... above.
（バキ）上からの命令だ
Huh...?
あ…
Their reasoning is...
風影かぜかげ様の不在が公になれば
if it becomes widely known that
if the Kazekage-sama is absent,
いつ よその里が攻めてきても
おかしくないという理由でな
there's no telling when other villages
will attack our village...
I can't believe this...
（砂の里の忍）そんな…
That's all the more reason that
だからこそ 一刻も早く
我愛羅を取り戻すべきではないのか
we have to get Gaara back
as soon as possible!
These Leaf people came
all this way
ここにいる木ノ葉の者たちも
for the very purpose of
going to Gaara's aid!
わざわざ 我愛羅を助けるために
来てくれているのだぞ
Gaara is our Kazekage, right?!
我愛羅は我々の風影ではないか
What's the point if we,
the Sand people, don't go to save him!
砂の人間が行かなくて
一体 どうする！
But...
（バキ）しかし…
I'm going.
（チヨ）わしが行く
The only Sand Shinobi
you need is me!
（チヨ）砂の忍は
わし１人で十分じゃ
チヨバア様
Grandmother Chiyo!
But that's...
あ… しかし それは…
I am already retired, you know...
もともと 隠居の身
I can do whatever I like.
どう行動しようと わしの勝手じゃ
そんな… 無理をなさらないほうが
You really shouldn't overdo it...!
Don't you dare treat me
like an old woman!
（チヨ）
わしを年寄り扱いするでないわい
たあっ！
あっ 飛んだ
She jumped!
（ナルト･サクラ）わっ！
Wha–?!
I haven't doted on my dear grandchild
for a while, after all...
かわいい孫を 久しぶりに
かわいがってやりたいんでの
All right, we'll head out.
（カカシ）
じゃあ 我々は出かけます
Sorry... I will try to convince
the higher-ups...
すまん
これから なんとか
上役たちを説得してみる
We'll follow behind later,
no matter what!
必ずあとから行くからな
（サクラ）うん
（ナルト）はっ そのころには
Gaara will be long rescued
by that time!
とっくに 我愛羅を
助け出してるってばよ
See you later!
（サクラ）いってきます
（カンクロウ）うっ
う… くっ
クソっ
Damn! If only I were
physically fit.
この体さえしっかりしてりゃ
There'd be no stopping me
from going...!
絶対に俺が行くってのに
Hey, we're going a little too fast!
（テンテン）
ちょっと飛ばしすぎだって
We haven't stopped running
since we left!
（テンテン）
もう ずっと走りっぱなしじゃない
Let's take a little break!
少しは休憩しようよ
Tenten, you need more training!
（ロック･リー）テンテン
修行が足りませんね
Lee! In front of you!
（日向ひゅうがネジ）リー 前だ
（リー）あっ
（マイト･ガイ）ああっ
（テンテン）あっ
Wait, Guy!
待て ガイ
（ガイ）んっ！ パックン
Pakkun!
Naruto!
ナルト
Can I ask you something?
１つ 聞いてもいい？
いつから暁に狙われてたの？
Since when have you been
targeted by the Akatsuki?
うっ
I don't know...
分かんねえ
There was that one time when
two people from the Akatsuki
（カカシ）１度 暁の中の２人が
ナルトに接触しに
木ノ葉まで来たことがあった
came to the Leaf Village in order to
make contact with Naruto.
But that was three years ago...
あれから３年
and they've just started
making a move now.
今になって動き始めた
I don't know why.
理由は分からないがな
Why did they wait three years?
どうして３年も待ったんだろ？
It could be that it's not because
they didn't want to,
（カカシ）
手を出さなかったんじゃなくて
but because they couldn't.
出せなかったのかもしれないな
Because Jiraiya-sama was always
hanging close to Naruto...
ナルトには 常に
自来也じらいや様がついていたからな
No...
（チヨ）いや
Based on information I acquired,
there apparently is another reason.
わしの得た情報では
もっと別の理由があると聞いた
Another... reason?
（ナルト）別の理由？
There's quite a bit of
preparation involved
人に封じられている
尾獣びじゅうを引き剥がすには
if one's gonna draw out the Tailed Beast
that's sealed within people.
それ相応の準備がいるからのう
They encountered difficulties
with that.
それに手間取ったのじゃ
What's this "Tailed Beast"
that you were talking about?
今の話… 尾獣って？
なんじゃ 綱手つなでの弟子のくせして
What?!
You're Tsunade's disciple
and you don't even know that?!
そんなことも知らんのかい
The Leaf Village had
a Nine-Tailed Fox Spirit...
木ノ葉には 九尾きゅうびがおったろうが
（ナルト）あっ
（サクラ）あっ
The Nine-Tailed Fox Spirit is
（カカシ）九尾のことは
木ノ葉では 完全に極秘扱いですので
treated as top secret
amongst the Leaf Village...
Well, that's not surprising, I guess...
まあ それもそうかのう
A Tailed Beast refers to
Beast Spirits with tails.
尾獣とは 尾を持つ魔獣のことじゃ
Long, long ago,
the Sand had a One-Tail.
砂は昔から一尾いちびを持っておる
That's the Shukaku sealed
within Gaara.
それが我愛羅に封じられた
守鶴しゅかくのことじゃ
One-Tail?
一尾
Do you mean that there are
other beasts
それじゃあ 九尾以外にも
そんな魔獣が？
besides the Nine-Tailed Fox Spirit?
（チヨ）そうじゃ
That's right...
There are a total of nine
tailed beasts in this world...
この世に 尾獣は全部で９体おる
Tailed beasts have
special characteristics.
尾獣には特徴があってな
Each of them have
a different number of tails.
それぞれ尾の数が違う
The One-Tailed has one tail.
The Two-Tailed has two.
一尾には尾が１本
二尾にびには２本
And up to the Nine-Tailed
as the name suggests,
それらが 九尾までその名のとおり
each name represents
the number of tails the beast has.
名が尾の数を表すのじゃ
The Tailed beasts have
immense Chakra
尾獣は バク大なチャクラの塊で
and in the world of Ninja,
忍界にんかい大戦期には 各国
隠れ里が軍事利用しようと
they were used for military purposes
by Hidden Villages around the world.
競って
手に入れようとしたものじゃ
They competed to get
their hands on them.
But no one was able
to control that power
しかし 人知を超えたその力を
制御することなど
which surpassed human intelligence.
誰にもできなんだ
I don't know why
the Akatsuki is after it,
暁がなんのために
それを欲しとるのか 分からんが
but that power is too dangerous...
危険すぎる力じゃ
But in this new peaceful age,
the Tailed beasts apparently...
まあ 平穏な情勢の中
時代も移ろい
今や尾獣は
still exist, having scattered
all around the world...
世界各地に ちりぢりに
存在しておるらしいがの
Kakashi directed us,
the Eight Ninja Hounds,
（パックン）
カカシに言われ わしら八忍犬はちにんけんは
to fan out in every direction
バラバラに八方に散り
暁の連中のにおいを追った
to follow the Akatsuki
Organization's scent.
そうしたところ…
While we were doing that,
we realized that
ヤツらは 木ノ葉と砂の間にある
川の国へと向かった
those guys were headed towards
the Land of Rivers
which is situated between
the Leaf and Sand.
川の国？
The Land of Rivers...?
そうじゃ
That's right.
In other words,
つまり 今現在
暁の最も近くにいるのは
you guys are closest to the Akatsuki
at this point in time.
木ノ葉から
砂へ向かってきていた...
You, who were heading from
the Leaf to the Sand Village.
お前らだ
（テンテン）あっ
I see...
なるほど
Follow me...
I'll explain the details as we run.
（パックン）わしについてこい
詳しいことは 走りながら説明する
All right! Let's go, everybody!
（ガイ）よし みんな 行くぞ
（テンテン）え～ もう？
Huh? Already?
An enemy is nearing
this hideout.
（ゼツ）このアジトの近くに
敵が近づいているぞ
An enemy, you said?
（デイダラ）敵だと？
And a highly skilled one at that.
（ゼツ）それも相当の手練れだ
His name is... Might Guy.
これは 名はマイト･ガイ
Who's that?
（暁リーダー）誰だ？ そいつは
（うちはイタチ）木ノ葉の上忍じょうにんで
体術を使う かなりのやり手だ
A Leaf Jonin who
uses Taijutsu.
He's one clever operator.
Don't underestimate him.
甘く見ないほうがいい
（干柿ほしがき鬼鮫きさめ）ああ～
Ah... that freak beast, huh...
あの珍獣ですか
We will use that Jutsu...
（暁リーダー）あの術をやる
In that case, I'll go...
（飛段ひだん）それなら俺が行く
I was getting irritated for not
having any luck finding a Jinchuriki.
人柱力じんちゅうりきが
なかなか見つからなくてな
イライラしてたところだ
No, I'll go...
（鬼鮫）いいや 私が行きましょう
I have something of a personal quarrel
with him, you see...
その人には個人的に
ちょっと因縁がありましてね
（暁リーダー）そうだな
You're right. That Jutsu is more suited
to someone like you.
あの術は 暁の中でも
チャクラ量の多いお前向きだからな
Among the Akatsuki,
you are more heavily loaded
with Chakra, Kisame.
鬼鮫
（鬼鮫）ハハッ はい
Yes...
Even so, I'll take 30%
of your Chakra.
（暁リーダー）それでも
チャクラの30パーセントはもらうぞ
（鬼鮫）ったく
Well, well, well...
やれやれ やっと…
It looks like I'll finally be
able to get pay back
あのときの蹴りの借りが
返せそうですね
for that kick he gave me...
Severe Leaf Hurricane!
（ガイ）木ノ葉剛力旋風このはごうりきせんぷう
（鬼鮫）うわあ！
（ガイ）ふっ
Who the hell is he?
何者です？
（ガイ）木ノ葉の気高き碧あおい猛獣
The Noble Blue Beast of
the Leaf Village... Might Guy.
マイト･ガイ
What's up?!
（ガイ）どうした？
Someone's coming!
（パックン）誰か来る
（テンテン）うっ
Byakugan!
白眼びゃくがん
Behind us!
後ろだ！
（テンテン）んっ
（リー）ハア
（ガイ）んっ
あっ
You...
お前は…
Do you know him, Guy-sensei?!
知ってるんですか？ ガイ先生
Who are you?
（ガイ）誰だ？
（テンテン）ああ…
Another guest...
（ゼツ）また来たぞ
It's a little noisy this time,
isn't it, Deidara!
（暁リーダー）今回は
やけに騒がしいな デイダラ
あ… いや
Well, the Jinchuriki was
stronger than the other two...
今回の人柱力は
ほかの２人より強かったんだよ うん
I told you at the start, didn't I?
（サソリ）
だから 俺が最初に言ったろうが
Your Jutsu wasn't suited
for covert operations.
お前の術は 隠密行動には
向いてねえってな
（デイダラ）はっ
そういう旦那のトラップも
I'd say your traps were
pretty loud too, weren't they?
結構 派手だったんじゃねえのか
うん
What!
（サソリ）なにを！
（暁リーダー）仲間割れはよせ
Stop fighting amongst yourselves!
Concentrate on the Jutsu!
今は術に集中しろ
さて 今度は誰が行く
Now then...
who should I send this time...
This time it's my turn,
without any doubt.
（飛段）今度こそ俺の番だな
（ゼツ）今度も木ノ葉の忍だ
Another Leaf Shinobi...
（飛段）チッ
Damn!
In that case, it's decided...
（暁リーダー）じゃあ 決まりだ
（カカシ）みんな止まれ！
Everybody, halt!
（ナルト）うっ
Who is that?
誰？
Out of the blue, huh...
（カカシ）いきなりですか
That guy... those eyes...
（チヨ）こヤツ あの目…
You're...
お前は…
This guy... has a ridiculous amount
of Chakra.
こいつ とんでもないチャクラ量だ
これほどのチャクラ量を
持ってるヤツを見たのは
I've never seen anyone besides
Naruto with that amount of Chakra.
ナルト以来だ
（リー）そんなに？
That much...?
本当に覚えてないと？
Are you really saying
you don't remember...?
あっ お前 まさか…
Don't tell me you're...!
思い出したようですね
It appears that you've remembered...
Have we met before?
俺と会ったことがあるのか？
珍獣は 頭のほうも
獣レベルのようですね
It looks like
the freak beast's intelligence
is at the level of a beast too...
Well... I'll make you
remember soon...
まあ すぐに思い出させて
差し上げますがね
Uchiha... Itachi!
うちはイタチ
あっ
Th-That guy is...
こ… この人が？
この人が… うちはイタチ
That guy is... Uchiha... Itachi!
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
♪～
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
I'm in my usual park.
koko wa itsumo no kouen
I can see the night scenery on the slide.
yakei ga mieru suberidai no ue
That's been my special seat for years.
mukashi kara boku no tokutouseki
Whenever I'm worried about something, I come here.
nayami ga areba koko ni kurun desu
Just like then, I'm on my way to my dreams.
ano koro no mama yume no tochuu de
But unable to fulfil them.
ima de kanaerarezu ni irun desu
Maybe this is the end of the line.
moshikashite koko ga mou shuuten
There are days when I say weak things like that.
nante yowane wo haite shimaisou na hi mo aru
But every time, I remember.
demo sono tabi ni omoidasu
That starry sky where I looked for a shooting star.
nagareboshi wo sagashite ano hoshizora
The wish I made when I was little hasn't changed even now.
chiisana koro no negaigoto ima mukashi mo kawaranai mama
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
～♪
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
Next Episode
What is that, Guy-sensei?!
あれは なんですか？ ガイ先生
リーよ あれこそが 我々の
待ち焦がれていたものだ
Lee, that is what we've been
waiting for!
では あれが
サーファーたちの憧れの的
Then that is what all
the surfers long for,
数年に１度やってくるという
伝説の大波
the legendary big wave that
arrives only once every few years...?!
ビッグサーズデイ！
Big Thursday! Go, Lee!
行け リーよ
今こそ あの荒れ狂う大波を制し
男になるチャンスだ
Now is your chance to conquer
that big wave
and become a man!
Yes, sir!
押忍！ 見ていてください
ガイ先生
Please watch Guy-sensei,
I'll prove to you my fighting spirit!
僕のファイティングスピリットを
証明してみせます
そのノリ やめなさい
Will you two stop talking
like that already?!
A Meeting With Destiny
次回「因縁
あいまみえる」
Next time: "A Meeting With Destiny"
Gallery of Memories
Today, I'll present you
with some treasured photos
（リー）今回は
木ノ葉に刻まれた 青春の思い出
秘蔵写真の数々を
僕が紹介していきますよ
of the Leaf's youthful memories.
First, this is the newborn Naruto-kun.
まずは 生まれたばかりのナルト君
There was even a time
when Naruto-kun was like this!
ナルト君にも
こんな時代があったんですね
Wow! This is a photo of the Third
and the Legendary Sannin.
なっ これは
３代目と伝説の３人です
ポニーテールの綱手様
とてもイケてます
Tsunade-sama sure looks cool
with a ponytail.
This is the Fourth
and Kakashi-san's team.
こちらは
４代目とカカシさんたちです
６歳で中忍ちゅうにんになったそうですよ
Kakashi became a chunin at age six.
さすが ガイ先生の永遠のライバル
It's easy to see why
he's Guy-sensei's eternal rival!
この写真は 今でも枕元に
大切に飾られているそうです
He displays this photo by his bed
even to this day.
では おなじみの方たちを
一気にご紹介です
Now then, I'll show you a bunch of photos
of people you're already very familiar with!
これは アカデミー生のころですね
This is when we were students
at the Academy.
うわ～ 懐かしいです
Wow... how nostalgic!
そして これがサクラさん
And this is Sakura-san!
のおお～！
ビュ… ビューティフルすぎです
Waw... she's too b-b-beautiful!
Her smile is so brilliant
I can't even look at the photo directly!
笑顔がまぶしすぎて
まっすぐ見られません
最後は りりしい眉に
ぱっちり おめめの美少
Last but not least, a handsome young man
with a gallant brow and large eyes.
That's right, the shining star
of the Leaf Village. That's yours truly!
そう 木ノ葉の美しき碧き野獣こと
この僕です
So cool.
T
o
b
e
c
o
n
t
i
n
u
e
d
.
決まった